<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Miller's Website</title>
    <description>My personal website. A place for my stuff.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 20:46:13 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 20:46:13 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ethical Considerations in Advanced Robotics and AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Advanced robotics and Artificial Intelligence is a very new area of scientific and sociological discussion. There wind up being a lot of problems with these kinds of products as they become increasingly complex, and when something goes wrong it’s not always clear whether responsibility lies with the user or with the manufacturer. I was inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2017/1/19/14322334/robot-electronic-persons-eu-report-liability-civil-suits&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;, where the author discussed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;important-terms&quot;&gt;Important Terms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI: Artificial Intelligence - A human-created entity that can respond to external stimuli in a way that is &lt;em&gt;comparable&lt;/em&gt; to a human in terms of sophistication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neural Network: Neural Net - A process that automatically uses feedback to improve itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-complexities-of-neural-networks&quot;&gt;The Complexities of Neural Networks&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time, you may have heard the term “neural network” when talking about engineering. This is the technology that drives a lot of the upcoming, more impressive products like Google’s self-driving cars. It’s a paradigm born of the need to develop software more complex than humans are able to wrap their mind around. I’m delving into this subject first, because understanding the basic ideas behind this technology is imperative to discussing the ethical implications further on down the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-are-neural-networks&quot;&gt;So what are neural networks?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neural networks are a new paradigm to programming that, rather than telling the computer what to do, tells it what you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; it to do. Rather than walk the computer through the process of following a task, you evaluate its performance at a task and it uses that feedback. This process is largely inspired by both how human beings learn things (by taking continuous feedback and linking it into how we do things) as well as the principles of evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, say you write a program to cook some pancakes. Because I like pancakes. In traditional programming, you would outline something like a recipe; it would go through all the steps, have clearly defined ingredients, quantities,  and cooking times. Then, once you eat the pancakes, you might go back and adjust the recipe for better pancakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using a neural network, the process is a bit different. You may start with a recipe, or even just a list of ingredients. Most likely, you’d program it with an initial, very basic recipe. Then, you’d develop a scoring system for the pancakes. Give some points for taste, nutritional value, and a relatively small number of points for deviation from the original recipe (so that as the “recipe” changes, it keeps making pancakes and doesn’t become completely indistinguishable). Next, it will take that original recipe and make minor random changes, and serves those modified recipes to people. If any score higher than the original, it uses that recipe going forward. Over time (with a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of samplings), the pancakes will be far superior to the original recipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-scary-side-of-neural-networks&quot;&gt;The Scary Side of Neural Networks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where things get kind of unnerving. Following the pancake metaphor, you’ll start to see the neural network doing really weird things that make no sense. If you start to look at the recipe, it will be extremely long and do things that make no sense. You’ll see seasonings that make no sense for pancakes, bizarrely complex ways of mixing batter, and other things that a human being would never do. Most likely, if a human tried to read the recipe they wouldn’t even be able to understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a case study where some scientists made a neural network to solve a relatively predictable problem; either solving an equation or navigating a maze, I don’t remember. After running the neural network for long enough, they found two things: 1) that the process followed was borderline gibberish and was extremely difficult to understand, and 2) that the algorithm was now so sophisticated that is was actually &lt;em&gt;taking advantage of previously undiscovered flaws in the hardware&lt;/em&gt; to optimize its speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as an algorithm becomes increasingly complex, it eventually goes beyond human comprehension, in unpredictable ways. This gives way to an important, and perhaps unanswerable question: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At what point of complexity, if any, are we forced to consider the possibility that an electronic device may be conscious?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add to this the fact that, using the internet, massive numbers of these robots or computers could be added together in a neural network. Imagine the skill of an individual who spent their entire life studying a trade. A neural network could have the equivalent of tens, or hundreds, or thousands of lifetimes of experience in a trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty much unanimous that the answer is “we’re not sure, but we’re pretty sure we’re not there yet”. Perhaps by following certain guidelines, we can find a way to ensure we never reach that point. It will give way to entirely new discussions about ethics and technology, the likes of which we’ve never seen. Further, it could introduce the problem of how human beings will function in a post-scarcity society, or a society where some are post-scarcity society, or even if a post-scarcity society is possible when labor becomes infinite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;legal-status-of-advanced-robotics&quot;&gt;Legal Status of Advanced Robotics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time goes on, it’s becoming apparent that we will need separate legal status for sufficiently dangerous equipment. The article above suggested tracking the possession of these robots using a kind of registry; this is an interesting idea. What if, like land, sufficiently advanced robots transferred ownership by way of a legal title or deed? It would allow one to track and identify the owner, in the case of one going rogue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But further, who gets held accountable when things go wrong? Say you had some highly-intelligent industrial equipment in a machine shop programmed using a neural net, that injured a worker?  Most would agree that the worker needs to be compensated, but should the legal owner of the robot or the machine be held accountable? It’s even possible that the neural net is part of a “hive mind” neural net, where all devices operate according to the same rules. This “hive mind” could be fully-distributed, where it has no owner, like the internet. Perhaps the manufacturer of the robot never even touched its programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in a system where a robot becomes as complex, or even more complex than a human being, could we hold that robot responsible? Further, if the robot is part of a hive mind, how can you hold anyone responsible? The hive mind is, at this point, beyond the control or understanding of any human being, but it’s also not sentient and is incapable of malicious intent. In this scenario, there are strong arguments that no one could be fairly held accountable, since the only point of failure was not controlled by any sentient being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, consideration of giving the status of a legal entity to the “hive mind” is necessary, because it must be held accountable for its actions, because no one else can. Then, it needs money, in order to compensate users when things go wrong. But this raises entirely new questions - how does it decide when to go to court and when to settle? Who argues for it in court - does it hire a “lawyer” hive mind? Does it have to pay the other “hive mind?” Does a human lawyer handle it? How could a human judge assess a being that they not only can’t understand, but can’t empathize with? What happens when a “hive mind” wrongs another “hive mind”? Where will the “hive mind” get its money from? Who does it charge? Would all this be decided by its original creator? Would it owe its original creator royalties? Can its original creator “disown” it (similarly to what happens with some “open-source” development projects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a lot to think about, and ultimately we won’t have any concrete answers until we get there. However, I’ve got a few ideas and principles that I believe could make things easier going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intentional creation of sentient beings should, at least at the beginning, be illegal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We need a definition of sentient for this context.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ultimately, I believe that the creation of special legal status (similar to corporations) for sufficiently intelligent artificial entities is necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How is a legal artificial entity different from a human, or a corporation? Can it declare bankruptcy? What legal rights and responsibilities does it have?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At exactly what point does a neural network become sufficiently detached from human control that an individual human can’t be held accountable?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/20/Ethical-Considerations-In-Advanced-Robotics-and-AI.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/20/Ethical-Considerations-In-Advanced-Robotics-and-AI.html</guid>
        
        <category>ethics</category>
        
        <category>advanced</category>
        
        <category>robotics</category>
        
        <category>ai</category>
        
        <category>artifical</category>
        
        <category>intelligence</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Secure Your Online Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have an online stalker who you’re worried might hack your account? Have sensitive materials in your accounts or computer
that you don’t want to be exposed to a threat? Just want to be safe in the modern day internet environment? Here you’ll
find some simple guidelines to stay safe out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As time goes on, personal information security has gotten more and more important, and knowing what exactly to do and
how to do it is difficult. For that reason, I’m making a short post about how to lock down your online life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;important-terms&quot;&gt;Important Terms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When talking about online security, there are some precise terms because of how new this field is. So I’ll cover some of
these here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encryption - Encryption is a process that scrambles data using a passcode. When data is properly encrypted with a secure password, it is unreadable by anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AES - The standard for “symmetric” encryption. This is what the NSA uses for top secret files, which should indicate its reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multi-Factor Authentication - The process of using multiple ways to verify that someone is who they say they are. For example,  a password (something only you should know), and a code texted to your phone (something only you should have). By verifying someone’s identity in multiple ways, you increase the barrier to entry of breaking into your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-1-password-manager&quot;&gt;Step 1. Password Manager&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/2017-01-17-LastPass.png&quot; alt=&quot;LastPass in action&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passwords in general have two main vulnerabilities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They’re usually made up of words, maybe with a number tacked on to the end. This becomes predictable, and makes easier to guess.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People often reuse the same password on multiple websites, so if an attacker gets one password, they get them all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best answer to these problems is a Password Manager. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;, because it’s truly cross-platform and affordable. &lt;a href=&quot;https://1password.com&quot;&gt;1Password&lt;/a&gt; is also popular. iCloud Keychain is built in to macs, and has some nice features as well, but is &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; on MacOS and iOS. Here’s what they do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember all of your passwords, securely encrypted in a “vault” with AES encryption.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lock that vault with one password - which means you only have to remember that one.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug in to web browsers and other apps and fill in your passwords automatically or with a prompt.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generate new, secure passwords that have a mix of letters, numbers, and symbols, and can be relatively long. Here’s an example: &amp;amp;B3BPBSNMKfus%9e*gy4. Good luck guessing that, hackers!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The result is that, as long as you guard your master password jealously, avoid reusing it where possible and use the generated passwords, your web life will be very secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, password managers have one important downfall: if your master password gets out, you can lose everything. Which is why you may also want to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-2-two-factor-authentication&quot;&gt;Step 2. Two-Factor Authentication&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/2017-01-17-Authy.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;What Authy looks like&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2-factor authentication can send a unique code to a device you own, to prove that you are who you say you are, when you first log in to a service from a new device or haven’t logged in for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically, this is a service you have to turn on in the web service you’re looking at. Usually it works by sending you a text with a one-time code that you can use to log in, but there are other solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.authy.com&quot;&gt;Authy&lt;/a&gt; as your “one-stop-shop” for this, as it works with a lot of websites, won’t fill up your text inbox, and works on iOS, Android, and Desktop. When setting up two-factor authentication on a website, look for “Google Authenticator”. It’ll give you a QR code - just scan it, and it’s set up! Note that some sites only support text for authentication, and not Google Authenticator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use this for LastPass, and now in order for someone to get into your account, it makes it &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; difficult to break into your account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Apple and Microsoft have their own ways for doing this for their accounts, that are in some ways more convenient and in some ways less so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;step-3-full-disk-encryption&quot;&gt;Step 3. Full Disk Encryption&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/2017-01-17-FileVault.png&quot; alt=&quot;FileVault&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a rather drastic step, but it has been made feasible by advances in technology. This will slow down your computer, but if you have a Solid State Drive (SSD) it isn’t particularly noticeable. The previous two steps can be considered sufficient for most people. This is turned on by default in Android and iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hard drive is where all your data is kept. Under normal circumstances, if someone steals this or your computer, they can read anything on it (that isn’t encrypted). Hackers have a saying: “Physical access is total access”. Of course, if there’s nothing interesting/private on your computer (that’s not encrypted already, like LastPass and Authy) this is a pointless exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows does this with BitLocker, and MacOS does this with FileVault. Both are excellent solutions (although Apple has a better record of not programming “back doors” in their software - which has lost them fans among the NSA and FBI and gotten them praise from privacy advocates). If these aren’t sufficient for you, you can do research and find your own solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats! With step 1 and 2, and proper diligence, your digital life is now locked down tight. If you followed step 3 as well, you’re Fort Knox 🎉.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/17/How-to-Secure-Your-Online-Life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/01/17/How-to-Secure-Your-Online-Life.html</guid>
        
        <category>online</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>cybersecurity</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2016 MacBook Pro Impressions</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I actually have some time on my hands, I’ll talk about Apple’s MacBook Pro line refresh. This refresh has long
been asked for in Apple circles, after the line has gone stale. It seems to me that Apple has largely transitioned away
from its computer line, treating them more as accessories to iPhone devices than as standalone products. It seems to me
that the new iterations of MacBooks are largely informed by this philosophy, in that they’re coming in with lower power
requirements, a smaller footprint, and longer battery life. They’re also coming with a larger price tag, something that
definitely has not been received well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this, I’ll discuss both the positives and negatives of the new hardware. This isn’t a fanboy’s explanation of why
these are Tim Cook’s greatest gift to mankind, nor is it a techie’s decrying of Apple’s risky decisions. I’m trying to
explore both the positive and negative aspects here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also note: I’m going to mostly talk with reference to the 15” models with touch bar, since it doesn’t make much sense
to me to talk about the incomplete feature set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;considerations-from-the-modern-computing-environment&quot;&gt;Considerations from the Modern Computing Environment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can probably skip this section, but when talking about features, I may reference it when making judgement calls
about why something is a good or bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The things that make a good consumer computer, in my opinion, have been changing rapidly. Computing power has become
ridiculously cheap, to the point where it’s often cheaper to rent computing power from Amazon or another cloud computing
service than it is to pay for the electricity bill to run your own. On the other hand, consumers are using laptops more
and more in their daily lives, making battery life and ease of use more and more important over computing power. People
use this fact daily (and Apple has done a bad job of adapting to this in some cases that I won’t cover here) without
even realizing it. Google Photos has computers that work on recognizing items in users’ photos so they can search by it.
Developers use cloud computing to run software builds and tests that can take hours on a fast machine. Graphics
professionals use cloud services to render animations, things that can take a very long time run locally. This allows
people to do complicated, powerful computations that would normally tie up their machine’s CPU for hours much faster,
without tying up their machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, cloud computing, when applied correctly, is faster, cheaper, and more convenient than running it on your local
computer, and it makes your computer’s processing power irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something else to consider is that we’re reaching the limit of the performance that can be achieved by single computers;
this is one of the factors that has been driving the migration towards cloud computing. Processing power used to roughly
double every 12 months, which turned to 18 months, which turned into 24, and now no longer really happens. We can only
manufacture transistors so small, and we can only cram so many fans and heat sinks into laptops. This means that, in
terms of specs, computers today aren’t that far ahead of computers a few years ago, which means upgrading regularly is
becoming less and less necessary. That’s not to say improvements haven’t been made, they just aren’t as dramatic as they
used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;model-variations&quot;&gt;Model variations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple is continuing their strategy of an effectively 3-tier product line - the feature-limited 13”, the 13”, and the 15”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feature-limited-13-macbook-pro&quot;&gt;Feature-Limited 13” MacBook Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The feature-limited 13” model starts at a steep $1500. This is a big step up, where this model previously sold at $1000.
It has a traditional function row instead of the touch bar, which many may find preferable. It has a 2.0GHz Dual-Code i5
CPU, 8GB (config to 16GB) memory, 256GB (config to 1TB) of SSD storage, and integrated Iris Pro graphics. It has weak
processing power, but if that’s not needed, it would be an acceptable work computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-featured-13-macbook-pro&quot;&gt;Full-Featured 13” MacBook Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model starts at $1800. It has the iconic touch bar, which is pretty much the #1 feature of the new models. It has a
reasonable 2.9GHz Dual-Core i5 CPU, 8GB (config to 16GB) memory, 256GB (config to 1TB) SSD, and integrated Iris Pro
graphics. It compares to the 15” models about as well as the previous years did; it’s noticeably weaker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;15-macbook-pro&quot;&gt;15” MacBook Pro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These computers are definitely the flagship, albeit with the nasty price point of $2400. It has a 2.6GHz Quad-Core i7
CPU (config to 2.9GHz), 16GB Memory, 256GB (config to 2TB) of SSD storage, and Radeon Pro 450 (config to 460) graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;form-factor&quot;&gt;Form Factor&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to talk about form factor first, because it’s the first interaction you’ll have with the computer. It’s very
thin, clocking in at about 1.5cm, and 3lbs for the 13”, or 4lbs for the 15”. A lot of people have decryed this, saying
they’d prefer using the internal space lost to put in more processing power or battery life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-touch-bar&quot;&gt;The Touch Bar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have talked about this being one of the new features for a while, and I have mixed feelings about it. I’ll say
this: Using a touch screen to replace the function row is certainly an interesting idea. Tim Cook has stated that he
doesn’t believe in putting touch screens on laptops’ main displays for user experience reasons, and I agree; why is for
another time. A lot of people are decrying it as foolish. As a developer, I’m inclined that direction; a lot of the
programs I use depend on the function row, and I don’t know for sure what will happen. A lot of people are particularly
unhappy because this will replace the physical escape key. Further, if you can touch-type function row, and use it
heavily in daily operations, this will be a big hit to your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this direction makes sense for Apple. Apple applications don’t often make great use of the function row, because
on macs those keys are primarily for media keys and other built-in functions, so doing something goofy with them almost
makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I actually like the idea of this feature. It lets individual apps customize what the touch bar can do, so
you won’t have to look up what the buttons do anymore. For something like photoshop, you could even put different tools
in the touch bar, freeing up the screen space for what you’re working on. For other things, you don’t need to remember
what “F6” does - there will be a picture right there on your keyboard. I believe we’ll see app developers come up with
a lot of interesting uses for the touch bar, and it’ll end up being a huge asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as touch-typing goes, I think it won’t be as big an issue as people usually consider it to be. While you don’t
have the tactile feedback on keypresses, you still have the rest of the keyboard as a touch-typing reference, in the
same way that you can touch-type on a phone once you’re used to holding it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-ports&quot;&gt;The Ports&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new MacBook Pros only have five ports (three on the feature-limited 13”), four Thunderbolt 3 / USB-C and a headphone
jack. These are replacing a lot, including USB 3.0, HDMI, SD-Card, Thunderbolt 2, and charging port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means, if you plug anything into your computer other than headphones, you will need some sort of adapter or dock.
However, each individual port can be used for 40 Gbps file transfer. That’s a lot. That’s enough to use two 4K displays
running at 60FPS at the same time off of one port, with bandwidth to spare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, the loss of moving towards the 1 port solution (USB-C is likely the future of everything, including data
transfer, displays, headphones, and more) is that for now, older technologies like HDMI and USB 2/3 need adapters to
work out of the box. It’s a growing pain of moving forward. That said, I think it was too soon to convert completely
to USB-C, and Apple should have waited another year or two to make that push. For example, for me, I depend too heavily
on HDMI, SD Cards, and Thunderbolt 1/2 to be able to switch to USB-C right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-specs&quot;&gt;The Specs&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m actually quite happy with the specs on the higher-end models. 2.6-2.9GHz i7 is reasonable for middle-high-end laptops,
which is exactly what the 15” MBPs are supposed to be. They also have 16GB Memory standard, which I think is
commensurate with that description. The lower models sporting 8GB also makes sense to me, because I think 8GB is
probably sufficient for most people. Of course, YMMV depending on what you’re doing. The lower-end models not having
upgradeable graphics is somewhat concerning, but not at all surprising. Graphics is one of the areas that can make a
huge difference in user experience, and so I find it disappointing. On the other hand, it seems more and more like the
13” pro line is less of a “pro” line and more Apple’s middle-end laptop line. On the other hand, the 15” models feature
discrete graphics cards across the board, which is another welcome change from the high-end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusions&quot;&gt;Conclusions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MacBook Pro line was in dire need of a refresh, and despite what the critics say, I don’t think Apple did a terrible
job here. They put decent specs on the higher-end computers to satisfy the high-end users, and added a big innovation in
user experience. Once people start using the touch bar, and application support of it matures, I suspect people will
find that it’s actually a useful tool and helpful to the workflow. Apple is always pushing the envelope on ports, so I
doubt the transition to thunderbolt 3 will be a particularly big deal. I suspect that, if anything, the price points
will be what hurts sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have voiced that they dislike the new laptops. Perhaps the funniest thing I saw was that it was
“highway robbery”. This comes down to something simple: if you don’t like it, don’t buy it. Believe me, if nobody buys
these, Apple will change their business strategies. You can still buy the old models refurbished (Apple has a great
refurb program - my current computer is a refurb) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/shop/browse/home/specialdeals/mac&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;will-you-buy-it&quot;&gt;Will You Buy It?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have asked me this. My answer is of course not. I’m a university student with a 15” 2012 MacBook Pro,
which has held up great over the years. It has all the power I need, and while there are a few improvements that I
definitely like about the new models (touch bar, fast ports), my current laptop is more than powerful enough to suit
my needs, and doesn’t require any modifications to work with my current setup. Likewise, if your current computer suits
your needs, don’t fix what ain’t broke. On the other hand, if you need a new computer and are willing to shell out the
big bucks, I think the new MacBook Pro is a fine choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/12/2016-Macbook-Pro-Impressions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/11/12/2016-Macbook-Pro-Impressions.html</guid>
        
        <category>macbook</category>
        
        <category>pro</category>
        
        <category>2016</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>impressions</category>
        
        <category>mac</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use Avahi to advertise an HTTP service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a simple guide to how to set up avahi to advertise an HTTP service that a web browser (in this case, Safari’s Bonjour) can detect and hook into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Background: This is running on a server running FreeBSD 10.3.0. Avahi was installed using pkg and set up with the default configuration.
It is used largely as a sandbox for experimenting, as well as being a media/file server and a light webserver.
Its capacity as a media server is fulfilled using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.plex.tv&quot;&gt;Plex&lt;/a&gt;, so I want to advertise the existence of the Plex server for easy use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install avahi with the package manager of your choice. In the case of FreeBSD and pkg, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pkg install avahi -y&lt;/code&gt;.
If using FreeBSD, you’ll need to enable the service by adding &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;avahi_daemon_enable=&quot;YES&quot;&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/rc.conf&lt;/code&gt;.
In GNU/Linux distros, this is typically not required.
The avahi service can now be started/stopped/restarted with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo service avahi-daemon &amp;lt;start/stop/restart&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, find the avahi services directory. With my installation, it is located in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/usr/local/etc/avahi/services&lt;/code&gt;.
On other GNU/Linux distros, it may also be found in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/avahi/services&lt;/code&gt;.
In the services directory, you will likely see some default services aleady set up.
For example, I already had &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sftp-ssh.service&lt;/code&gt; amd &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh.service&lt;/code&gt; in mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new file called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;your-service&amp;gt;.service&lt;/code&gt;. In my case, this is &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;plex.service&lt;/code&gt;.
Within that file, add the following (which I shamelessly stole most of from &lt;a href=&quot;http://holyarmy.org/2008/01/advertising-linux-services-via-avahibonjour/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; standalone='no'?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!--*-nxml-*--&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE service-group SYSTEM &quot;avahi-service.dtd&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;service-group&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;replace-wildcards=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;yes&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;%h &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;YOUR_HTTP_SERVICE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;service&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;type&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;_http._tcp&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/type&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;port&amp;gt;&amp;lt;YOUR_PORT&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/port&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/service&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/service-group&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, restart avahi with the command &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo service avahi-daemon restart&lt;/code&gt;.
The new service will now be viewable via bonjour clients, such as Safari and dns-sd (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/2016-09-26-avahi-in-safari.png&quot; alt=&quot;Avahi-Safari&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/2016-09-26-avahi-in-terminal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Avahi-dns-sd&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/26/Avahi-HTTP-Service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/09/26/Avahi-HTTP-Service.html</guid>
        
        <category>avahi</category>
        
        <category>bonjour</category>
        
        <category>zeroconf</category>
        
        <category>plex</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jurassic World with Chris Pratt as the Velociraptors and a Velociraptor as Chris Pratt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/2016-09-24-jurassic-world-reversal.png&quot; alt=&quot;Jurassic World with Chris Pratt as the Velociraptors and a Velociraptor as Chris Pratt&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/24/Jurassic-World-Reversal.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/09/24/Jurassic-World-Reversal.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Dramatic Re-enactment of the iPhone 7's Development Pitch</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;T is Tim Cook. All others’ positions are inferred by context. This is just a fun little script I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “We need better photo quality.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A: “Really? I think users care more about-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sniper Apple keeps across the street to monitor its engineers takes out A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: “Photo quality is my top priority!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Okay, good. What can we do about it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: “Well, people like zooming in, but digital zoom sucks. We could work on that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Ooh, I like that. What do we need to do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: “Well, if we made it physically a little bigger-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A red dot appears just on the left of C’s center of mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: “But that would be silly. Instead, we’ll add an &lt;em&gt;ENTIRE SECOND CAMERA&lt;/em&gt; that has a different zoom built-in!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “I love it. What else do you have?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B: “Let’s add wide color; our users have wanted for years-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;B’s brains splatter against the wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Gary, he kind of had a point, that’s actually a good idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;G: “Sorry boss. I heard ‘our users have wanted it for years’ and assumed it was go time.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Normally a safe assumption, but I’m afraid you were wrong on this one. Harvey, go for it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second sniper takes out Gary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;H: “Done, boss.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Excellent. Now back to the task at hand; what else can we do?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C: “We could custom build a special, extra chip dedicated solely to taking good pictures.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “You better not be about to tell me we have to make the phone bigger.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A red dot appears on D’s temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C: “Of course not boss! Remember when we got rid of the DVD drive and people were mad but we called it ‘innovative’? What if we made extra space… by getting rid of the headphone jack!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tim Cook’s jaw drops, flabberghasted by C’s utter &lt;em&gt;genius&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “That’s the best idea I’ve ever heard. I can’t believe it - I finally get to pull a ‘Steve Jobs’.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Now - that’s almost enough for the next release, but I think we need a bit more. What more can we do to improve image quality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C: “I’ve got you. Check this out - what if we double our processing power, and just make micro-optimizations with that until it looks good?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Like a college student pounding coffees until their term paper is done.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C: “Exactly.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Well, I’m satisfied. Start manufacturing. Unfortunately, C, we need to protect our secrecy, and non-disclosure agreements just aren’t enough anymore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey shoots C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “Excellent job Harvey. I knew hooking up a mic in the room to your Apple® AirPods™ would pay off. Unfortunately-“&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harvey gets taken out by a third sniper, Ivan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/images/posts/yeah.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T: “-you only get 5 hours of life with them.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/14/A-Dramatic-Reenactment-of-the-iPhone-7's-Development-Pitch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/09/14/A-Dramatic-Reenactment-of-the-iPhone-7's-Development-Pitch.html</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        <category>7</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        <category>pitch</category>
        
        <category>funny</category>
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>09/07 Apple Event Coverage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’ll do my regular coverage of the Apple event now that I’ve sat on it a few days, broken into relevant subsections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apple-watch&quot;&gt;Apple Watch:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Added a new iteration, called “Series 2”, and one that’s basically the same but with a processor update, “Series 1”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Processor update to both. Nothing truly substantial, but it will help future-proof it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Series 2 is waterproof and has built-in GPS. This makes it more usable for fitness without an iPhone nearby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Series 2 has a much brighter display, for better in-sun visibility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Price point for series 1 has dropped to $270. Price delta for 42/38 mm models has dropped from $50 to $30.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They got it pretty much right the first time, and there’s not a whole lot to improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;iphone&quot;&gt;iPhone:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Substantial camera improvements. 7 has image stabilization, and 7+ has dual lenses. This means that iPhone can now physically zoom, and better correct digital zoom. Also has better image software to improve low-light shots and overall image prettiness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End-to-end wide-color gamut support. This means you’ll get brighter, sharper colors across the board.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CPU upgrade - There’s been a massive CPU upgrade, with not just huge performance increases, but battery life increases. I’ll discuss implications later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loss of headphone jack - this gets its own section with in-depth analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t like it don’t buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-headphone-jack&quot;&gt;The Headphone Jack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loss of headphone jack. You’ve heard about it. You might be mad about it. Personally, the reaction reminds me of when Apple migrated away from optical drives (or from floppy disks, but I wasn’t there for that). One difference is that back then I thought Apple was right to remove the optical drive - but I don’t think so here. The optical drive had a clear replacement - digital distribution. Tim Cook kind of flubbed on what we’re supposed to replace aux with, between bluetooth and lightning. Both cases had a poorly received alternative (external DVD drive / lightning-aux converter) I actually could’ve gotten behind this decision if it had been made a bit differently; delayed by maybe 1 or 2 years to address the faults. Fault 1: There is no good replacement for Aux. Bluetooth’s quality is weak - waiting for bluetooth 5.0 could’ve helped a lot. Lightning is a poor replacement for wired - it’s little used and nonstandard. I have little doubt this is a licensing power grab by Apple. Converting to USB-C would’ve spoken to their willingness to move on from outdated and obsolete technology. Fault 2: No charging while listening. It’s theorized that Apple was working on built-in wireless charging for the iPhone. If that were on the scene, this move would make a lot more sense. Given those 2 things, I think this change would be much better (although no better received). The third fault is that most of the consumer world still runs on aux, but this will still be the case 2 years from now (if Apple hadn’t made this move). USB-C would be a better audio driver than aux. It’s better than lightning. I think Apple is making a good stand, but on the wrong foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;processor-implications&quot;&gt;Processor implications:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I’m excited about. There’s something in computer science called “Moore’s Law” which derives to “Computer power roughly doubles every year”. Later, it was changed to 18 months as we came closer to hitting the limits of what we could do. Now, the law is more or less obsolete - we can’t do much more in some arenas to make circuitry smaller. Apple has been doing a lot of work on low-power ARM chips (like A10) over the last few years, doing some impressive things. This improvement alone is cool, but I’m looking forward to what this chip will accomplish on the iPad Pro models. Unfortunately by the iPad Pro, it now has the specs of a full computer, but not the OS. I personally suspect work on an “iOSX” project for the iPad Pros, which I believe would make them some of the most popular computers out there. But making a fully-functional touch-based OS with a good UI is hard - just ask Windows 8.
So overall this year was disappointing, but had some cool things in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/10/0907-Apple-Event-Coverage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/09/10/0907-Apple-Event-Coverage.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Excerpts from Apple's Review Guidelines</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;From this document: &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&quot;&gt;https://developer.apple.com/app-store/review/guidelines/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“…if your app is plain creepy, it may not be accepted”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We have lots of serious developers who don’t want their quality Apps to be surrounded by amateur hour.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“We will reject Apps for any content or behavior that we believe is over the line. What line, you ask? Well, as a Supreme Court Justice once said, “I’ll know it when I see it”.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“If you run to the press and trash us, it never helps.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/23/Excerpts-from-Apple's-Review-Guidelines.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/23/Excerpts-from-Apple's-Review-Guidelines.html</guid>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>review</category>
        
        <category>guidelines</category>
        
        <category>funny</category>
        
        <category>humor</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
